Guide to the Wesley C. Salmon Papers, 1950-2003 ASP.2003.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Professional Talks, 1970-2001; III.
  - "New Look at Causality": Konstanz, Munich, and Heidelberg, undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - "New Look at Causality": University of Notre Dame, 1981 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - "New Model of Statistical Explanation in Science", undated (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - "New Models of Scientific Explanation": Society for American Archaeology, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - "Objective Probabilities: Propensities vs. Frequencies": University of Michigan and Indiana University, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - "Ornithology in a Cubical World: Reichenbach on Scientific Realism": Boston Colloquium and UCLA, 1991 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - "Perspective": Honors Convocation, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - "Philosophy of Bertrand Russell": Pittsburgh British Festival, 1981 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - "Philosophy of Geometry": Math and Everything Else Series, 1970-1971 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - "Philosophy of Physics: Problems and Approaches", undated (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - "Plato and Mathematics", undated (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - "Plausibility Arguments in Science": University of Montana, 1968 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - "Plausibility Arguments in Science": Museum of Northern Arizona, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - "Plausibility vs. Inexorable Laws": Scientific Controversies International Conference, 1993 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - "Priori Knowledge": Pittsburgh, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - "Probabilistic Causality": Indiana University, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - "Probabilistic Explanation": PSA Conference, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - "Probabilistic vs. Indeterministic Causality": University of Iowa, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - "Probability and Induction": Pittsburgh Lectures, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - "Probability of Scientific Theory", undated (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - "Problem of Induction": London Symposium, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - "Problem of Statistical Explanation": AAAS Meeting, 1967 (Box 50, Folder 24)
  - "Puzzles About Confirmation": Kentucky University, 1972 (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - "Quasars, Causality, and Rhetoric": Centro Fiorentino, 1993 (Box 50, Folder 26)
  - "Ragionamento Informale e Regole Formali": Rome, 1991 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "Ragionamento Informale e Regole Formali": Pisa, 1991 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Ragionamento Informale e Regole Formali": University of Catania, 1992 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - "Rationality and Objectivity in Science": Philosophy of Science Center and Western Canada Philosophy Association, 1986-1987 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - "Rationality and Objectivity in Science", 1989 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - "Rationality in Science": Carleton College and University of Minnesota, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - "Rational Prediction": Popper Symposium, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - "Realism and Scientific Explanation": USC, March 3rd, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - "Realistic Account of Causation": Genoa Conference, November 1999 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - "Relative Utility of Deductive and Inductive Logic": Conference on Logic and Liberal Learning, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - "Russell on Scientific Method": Russell Conference, March 1972 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - "Russell's Philosophical Accomplishment": Russell Memorial, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - "Science: Rational or Irrational": University of California Santa Cruz, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - "Scientific Evidence and the Existence of God": Pittsburgh Lectures, 1969 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - "Scientific Explanation": Southern Methodist University, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - "Scientific Explanation: Causation and Implication": Mexico City Conference, 1990 (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - "Scientific Explanation: Causation and Unification": University of Nebraska, 1989 (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - "Scientific Explanation": Consensus or Progress?": AAAS Symposium, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - "Scientific Knowledge vs Scientific Understanding": Sigma Xi, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - "Scientific Realism: Logic, Physics, Metaphysics": International Conference Logic and Metaphysics, 2001 (Box 51, Folder 20)
  - "Scientific Understanding and Human Values": International Conference on Ethical Research and the Sciences, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 21)
  - "Scientific Understanding in the Twentieth Century": Oregon State University and Einstein Forum, 1994-1995 (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - "Scientific Understanding in the Twentieth Century", 1997 (Box 51, Folder 23)
  - "Scientific Understanding in an Indeterministic World": Mt. Saint Mary's and Centro Fiorentino, 1990 (Box 51, Folder 24)
  - "Scientific Understanding in the Twentieth Century": Vienna Institute, May 1999 (Box 51, Folder 25)
  - "Significance of One Way Speed of Light": Melbourne, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 26)
  - "Simultaneity Now", undated (Box 51, Folder 27)
  - "Spirit of Logical Empiricism": Center, 1998 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - "Statistical and Causal Relevance in Scientific": Pittsburgh Workshop, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - "Statistical Relevance Explanation": Rockefeller Seminar, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - "Structure of Causal Explanation": University of Coruna, 2001 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - "Theoretical Explanation": Bristol Philosophy Conference, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - "Theoretical Explanation": APA Pacific Division Symposium, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - "Theoretical Explanation": University of Notre Dame, 1981 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - "Third Dogma of Empiricism": University of Pittsburgh, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - "Third Dogma of Empiricism":Montana University, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - "Three Conceptions of Explanation": Simon Fraser University, 1979 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - "Universe", 1995 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Untitled Lecture: Athens, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Untitled Lecture: Clemson College, 1997 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Untitled Lecture: Hamilton College, 1986 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Untitled Lecture: International Conference of Philosophy of Science, 1988 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Untitled Lecture: International Wittgenstein Symposium, undated (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - Untitled Lecture: Minnesota Conference on Induction, 1968 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Untitled Lecture: NEH Seminar, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Untitled Lecture: Princeton University, 1987 (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Untitled Lecture: Second International Conference on History and Philosophy of Science, 1978 (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - Untitled Lecture: Temple University, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - Untitled Lecture: UCLA Colloquium, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 22)
  - Untitled Lecture: USC, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 23)
  - Untitled Lecture: Virginia Tech, 1988 (Box 52, Folder 24)
  - "Values in Science": Ideal or Illusion Conference, 2001 (Box 52, Folder 25)
  - "What is Scientific Explanation?": University of Wyoming, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 26)
  - "What Makes Scientific Understanding Special": Hampen-Syndey College, Cal-State, and University of Washington, 1991-1993 (Box 52, Folder 27)
  - "What's next Dammit, David Hume?": Oberlin Conference, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 28)
  - "Why Ask Why": APA Presidential Address, 1978 (Box 52, Folder 29)
  - "Why Do Physicists Believe What They Believe?": University of Arizona, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 30)
  - "Wisdom and Science": Northwestern University, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 31)
- Teaching Materials, 1951-2001; IV.
  This series contains lecture notes, overhead projections, tests, and quizzes that Salmon used in his teaching. The material is chiefly from courses taught during his time as a professor at the University of Pittsburgh, but there are materials from his earlier posts. There may be several different versions of material for the same course given in different years and these may reflect changes in his views on topics covered in the syllabus of the course.
  - Academic Positions and Visiting Appointments, 1950-2001; 1.
    - University of California at Los Angeles, 1950-1951 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - State College of Washington, 1951-1954 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Northwestern University, 1954-1955 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Brown University, 1955-1963 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - University of Washington, 1956 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - University of Bristol, 1959 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - University of Minnesota, 1963 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - University of Chicago, 1966 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - University of Indiana, 1963-1973 (Box 53, Folder 9-10)
    - University of Indiana-Doctoral Committee Advisor, 1963-1973 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - University of Indiana-NSF Research Grant "Probability, Frequency, and Induction", 1963-1966 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - University of Indiana-NSF Research Grant "The Logic of the Microcosm", 1965-1969 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - University of Indiana-NSF Research Grant "Foundations of Inference in Empirical Science", 1969-1971 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - University of Arizona, 1973-1981 (Box 53, Folder 15-18)
    - University of Arizona-Committee of the History and Philosophy of Science, 1976-1981 (Box 54, Folder 1-3)
    - University of Arizona-Lecture Committee, 1976-1981 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - University of Arizona- Foundation, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - University of Arizona-NSF Reserach Grant "Unified Theory of Scientific Explanation", 1977-1981 (Box 54, Folder 6-8)
    - University of Arizona-NSF Research Grant "Casual and Theoretical Explanation in Science", 1974-1977 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - University of Melbourne, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - University of British Columbia, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - University of Pittsburgh, 1981-2001 (Box 55, Folder 1-6)
    - University of Pittsburgh- Annual Reports, 1981-2000 (Box 55, Folder 7-8)
    - University of Pittsburgh- Sabbatical, 1987-1988 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - University of Pittsburgh-Meetings with the Dean, 1981-1984 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - University of Pittsburgh-Center for Philosophy of Science, 1981-1985 (Box 55, Folder 11-12)
    - University of Pittsburgh-Chairman of the Department of Philosophy, 1980-1983 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - University of Pittsburgh-Graduate Committee, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - University of Pittsburgh- Public Service Awards Committee, 1997 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - University of Pittsburgh-Tenure Council, 1983-1985 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - University of Pittsburgh-Hempel Farewell, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - University of Bologna, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - University of Konstanz, 1995-1996 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Offers and Inquires, 1966-1976 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Course Materials, 1950-2000; 2.
    - Carnap and Reichenbach Seminar, 1990-1991 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Causality, 2000 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Confirmation/Induction/Probability-PHIL 2690, 1994 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Confirmation Theory Seminar-PHIL 289, 1988 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Core Corses in Phil. of Science. Phil 2600/HPS 2501, undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Development of Scientfifc Empiricism- PHL 168, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Explanation- PHIL396H, 1976-1977 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Explanation Seminar, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Explanation and Causality- PHIL 596H, 1979-1980 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - History of Moral Philosophy- PHIL 410, 1980-1981 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Honors Introduction for Engineers- PHIL 72, 1982-1983 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Inductive Logic and Probability- PHIL109, 1975 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Introduction to Logic- PHIL A, 1954-1955 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Introduction to Logic- PHIL 11,PHIL 11: 1968-1988 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Introduction to Logic- PHIL 11,PHIL 11: 1968-1988 (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Introduction to Philosophy of Science- PHIL 105, 1975 (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Introduction to the Philosophy of Science- PHIL 180, 1984-1990 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Introduction to the Philosophy of Science- PHIL 180, 1984-1990 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Introduction to the Philosophy of Science- PHIL 205, 1979 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Introduction to the Philosophy of Science- PHIL 305, 1980 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Introduction to the Philosophy of Science-PHIL 1610, 1990-1994 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Introduction to the Philosophy of Science-PHIL 1610, 1990-1994 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Introduction to the Philosophy of Science-PHIL 1610, 1990-1994 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Leonardo, Galileo, and Other Italian Scientists-PHIL 1690, 1994-1999 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Leonardo, Galileo, and Other Italian Scientists-PHIL 1690, 1994-1999 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Leonardo, Galileo, and Other Italian Scientists-PHIL 1690, 1994-1999 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Leonardo, Galileo, and Other Italian Scientists-PHIL 1690, 1994-1999 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Leonardo, Galileo, and Other Italian Scientists-PHIL 1690, 1994-1999 (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Leonardo, Galileo, and Other Italian Scientists-PHIL 1690, 1994-1999 (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - PHIL 210, 1973-1974 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - PHIL 409, 1979-1980 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - PHIL 494, 1983-1984 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Philosophy and the Rise of Modern Science-PHIL 102, 1984-1998 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Philosophy and the Rise of Modern Science, PHIL 102, 1982-1984 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Philosophy of Science- PHIL 150, 1982-1984 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Philosophy of Science- PHIL 150 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Philosophy of Science, PHIL 314A, 1983-1984 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Philosophy of Science Core Course-PHIL 287, 1985-1989 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Philosophy + The Rise of modern Science PHIL 1600, 1998 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Philosophy of Science Core Seminar-PHIL 2600, 1990-1998 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Philosophy of Science Core Seminar-PHIL 2600, 1990-1998 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Probability and Induction-PHIL 155, 1981-1982 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Probability and Induction-PHIL 289, 1983-1984 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Realism Seminar- PHIL 2681, 1997 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Russell's Philosophy of Science- PHIL 455, 1972-1973 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Scientific Explanation- PHIL 285, 1990-1997 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Scientific Explanation and Causality- PHIL 288, 1981-1982 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Scientific Explanation and Scientific Realism- PHIL 2675, 1993 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Scientific Explanation and Scientific Realism- PHIL 2675, 1997 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Scientific Realism- PHIL 290, 1987 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Space and Time/ Philosophy of Math-PHIL 681, 1970 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Personal Material, 1950-2001; 3.
    - Curriculum Vitae and Accomplishments, 1950-2001 (Box 60, Folder 13-15)
    - Diplomas, undated (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - Awards and Press, 1981-1995 (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - In Memory of Wesley C. Salmon, 2001 (Box 60, Folder 18)
- Professional Organizations, 1960-2000; V.
  This series contains materials that document Salmon's work with professional organizations within the discipline of Philosophy. There is correspondence as well as conference programs, and discussions of organizational administration.
  - American Association of the Advancement of Science, 1982-1985 (Box 61, Folder 1-2)
  - American Association of the Advancement of Science- Section L, 1983-1986 (Box 61, Folder 3-4)
  - American Association of the Advancement of Science- Meeting, May 1968 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1979-1989 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1982-1986 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - American Philosophical Association- Executive Committe Pacific Division, 1974-1978 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - American Philosophical Association- Pacific Division Vice President, 1976-1978 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - American Philosophical Association- Eastern Division, 1981 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - American Philosophical Association- Board of Officers, 1977-1983 (Box 61, Folder 11-12)
  - American Philosophical Quarterly, 1964-1986 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - British Society for the Philosophy of Science, 1973-1977 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Carnap and Reichenbach Colloquium Committee, 1991 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Division of History of Science- Meeting, 1996 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Division of History of Science- Meeting, July 1997 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Division of History of Science- Meeting, Dec. 1997 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science, 1961-1963 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Bureau Matters, 1959-1965 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Executive Committee Matters, 1963-1965 (Box 62, Folder 9-10)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Past Activities, 1963-1965 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Planned Activities, 1965 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- General Assemblies, 1958-1967 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Joint Symposium, 1964 (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Correspondence with Member Countries, 1964-1965 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Finnish National Committee, 1960-1972 (Box 62, Folder 16)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science, 1970-1973 (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science, 1978-1983 (Box 63, Folder 1-5)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- 8th Congressional Program Committee, 1987 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- 10th Congress, 1995 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Liege Meeting, 1997 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Joint Commission Committee, 1994 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Executive Committee, 1996-1998 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Joint Conference, 1998 (Box 63, Folder 11-12)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- 11th Congress, 1999 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Ethics Symposium, 1999 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Post Congress Finances, 1999 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- New Executive Committee, 1999-2000 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Joint Conference, 2000 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- 12th Congress, 2000 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Division of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science- Treasurer, 1996-1999 (Box 64, Folder 7-8)
  - Erkenntnis, 1976-1990 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - International Council of Scientific Unions- Varia, 1963-1966 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - International Council of Scientific Unions- General Committee Meeting, 1996 (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - International Council of Scientific Unions- General Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Journal of Philosophical Logic, 1973-1985 (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Konstanz Program, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 1-2)
  - National Academy, 1967 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - National Science Foundation Oversight Committee, 1981-1986 (Box 65, Folder 4-5)
  - Pacific Philosophical Quarterly, 1979 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Philosophy of Science, 1964-1981 (Box 65, Folder 7-8)
  - Philosophy of Science- Search Committee, 1974-1992 (Box 65, Folder 9-10)
  - Philosophy of Science- Complaints, 1973 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Philosophy of Science Association, 1967-2000 (Box 66, Folder 1-3)
  - Philosophy of Science Association- Lansing Meeting, 1972 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Philosophy of Science Association- Research Support Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Philosophy of Science Association- International Union of History and the Philosophy of Science, 1971-1972 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Philosophy of Science Association- Pittsburgh Conference Program, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Philosophy of Science Association- International Center, 1972 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Philosophy of Science Association- AAAS Relations, 1971-1972 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Philosophy of Science Association- IUS Merger, 1971 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Philosophy of Science Association- Financial Reports, 1973 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Philosophy of Science Association- Notre Dame, 1974 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Philosophy of Science Association- Nominating Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy of Science Association- Reorganization Committee, 1990 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Philosophy of Science Association- Presidential, 1970-1974 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy of Science Association- Meeting, 1984 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Pittsburgh- Konstanz Center Publication Committee, 1988-1991 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Synthese Library Editorial Board, 1966-1974 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Synthese Editorial Committee, 1965-1991 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - United States National Committee-IUHPS, 1962-1966 (Box 67, Folder 8-9)
  - United States National Committee- IUHPS Meeting, 1964-1967 (Box 67, Folder 10-11)
  - United States National Committee- IUHPS Ad Hoc Sub Committee, 1964 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - United States National Committee- IUHPs Congress, 1967 (Box 13)
- Photographs of Salmon and Colleagues, 1951-2001; VI.
  This series contains a number of photographs of Salmon. The photographs are often group photographs - usually of Salmon and his professional colleagues; however, some are portraits of Salmon by himself. The group photographs show working groups or discussion groups at conferences or other professional gatherings. In many of the photographs not all subjects have been formally identified; plus the photographer was not always identified.
  - Salmon with Globe at Math and Everything Else Lecture, 1971 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Group Photo from NSF Conference on Probability and Causation, July 1985 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Publicity Photos of Salmon, undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Salmon Accepting an Award, undated (Box 68, Folder 4)
- Library Materials, 1970-2001; VII.
  This series contains a relatively small number of annotated books from Salmon's library. These are all on philosophical topics and are sometimes by Salmon himself, or by philosophers closely associated with his fields of inquiry. While there may be underlining in some books, books whose annotations were solely underlined were not preserved in this series. Annotations here was used to mean commentary by Salmon.
  - Annotated Books by Salmon and others, 1960-2000; 1.
    This subseries contains a relatively small number of books written both by Salmon and others that were either annotated or otherwise contain information useful to a researcher.
    - Galavotti, Maria Carla. Probabilita. Milano: La Nuova Italia, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Grunbaum, Adolf. The Foundations of Psychoanalysis. Berkeley, CA: University of California Press, 1984 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Grunbaum, Adolf. Modern Science and Zeno's Paradoxes. London: George and Allen Unwin, 1967 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Grunbaum, Adolf. Validation in the Clinical Theory of Psychoanalysis. Madison, Conn.: International Universities Press, Inc., 1993 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Humphreys, Paul. The Chances of Explanation. Princeton, N.J.: Princeton University Press, 1989 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Parrini, Paolo. Conoscenza E Realta.Gius: Laterza and Figli, 1995 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Parrini, Paolo. Knowledge and Reality. Boston: Kluwer Academic Publishers, 1998 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Reichenbach, Hans. Nomological Statements and Admissible Operations. Amsterdam: North-Holland Pub. Co, 1954 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Reichenbach, Hans. T he Philosophy of Space and Time. New York: Dover, 1958 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Reichenbach, Maria. Hans Reichenbach Selected Writings, 1909-1953. Boston: D. Reidel Publishing Co., 1978 (Box 70, Folder 5)